#### **DAVID FRANCIS GITHAGUI MICHEKE**

Tel: +254 (0) 720 764 774 Email: <u>micheked@gmail.com</u> P.O Box 350 - 00902, Kikuyu, Kenya

#### **CAREER PROFILE SUMMARY**

I have been an Equities & Derivatives trader with exposure in the financial markets for a decade.

Professionally, I started out as a global research analyst and ended up as a local equities and derivatives trader. I researched structured notes, mutual funds, and exchange-traded funds. I also managed the client's foreign investment portfolios and guided the direction of investments in order to produce greater returns.

Presently, I specialize in the technical analysis of US indices and gold, identifying potential market direction.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor Degree in Business and information Technology (BBIT)**

Multimedia University College of Kenya, (MMU), 2010 (not completed)

## Degree in International Business Administration – Finance & Entrepreneurship

United States International University, (USIU), 2006 (on going)

## **Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education**

Aga Khan High School, 2002-2005

## **Kenya Certificate of Primary Education**

Kilimani Primary School, 1993-2001

#### PROFESSIONAL COURSES/TRAININGS

## **Certificate in Derivatives Dealer**

Nairobi Securities Exchange (NSE), 2019

#### **Certificate in Financial Modelling**

Lattice Training Ltd, 2018

## Certificate in Regulations & Market Practise (Kenya)- CISI 2

Chartered institute for Securities & Investment (CISI), 2017

## Certificate in International Introduction to Securities & Investment (Kenya) - CISI 1

Chartered institute for Securities & Investment (CISI), 2016

### **Certificate in Automated Trading System**

Nairobi Securities Exchange (NSE), 2016

## **KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES ACQUIRED**

- Equity & Derivatives Trading
- Foreign Exchange Trading
- Performing client due diligence
- Risk & Financial Analysis
- Investment Advise
- Client Management

#### Other skills/abilities:

- Good Presentation Skills
- Originative
- Market Analysis
- Excellent Communication & Interpersonal skills

## **WORK HISTORY**

Introducing Broker FBS Inc, Jan 2023 – April 2024

## **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Successfully prospecting and qualifying new sales leads as an introducing broker with FBS.
- Actively analyzing the forex market to make informed trading decisions.
- Training clients on how to start trading forex.

# Equity & Derivatives Trader Genghis Capital Ltd, Aug 2016 – Dec 2022

## **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Grow the client base and revenue as per the set targets.
- Review all securities transactions to ensure accuracy of the information and that trades conform to regulations of NSE.
- Ensure appropriate response and resolution of queries and requests by clients within agreed timelines.
- Provide market and investment information and advice to the Sales and Discretionary Portfolio
   Management team on the purchase and sale of particular Securities.
- Up-to-date knowledge and use of the ATS system to ensure maximum efficiencies are achieved on the utilization of the ATS platform.
- Develop trading strategies by reviewing investment information, and monitoring market conditions from the Trading floor, and through contact with trading departments of other investment firms (Brokerage houses), Fund managers and Financial Analysts.
- Analyze market conditions to determine the right time to execute transactions.
- Monitor active orders for risk and optimal tactic selection
- Manage order flow from clients ensuring smooth processes and swift transactions

#### **Key Achievement:**

- Involved in the partnership between EGM Securities & Genghis Capital, enabling our clients to have exposure to the global markets.
- > In-charge of establishing Derivatives trading in Genghis Capital.

# Senior Research Analyst Genghis Capital Ltd, Jun 2015 – April 2016 Duties and Responsibilities

- Supervisorial oversight of the Department, liaising with Offshore providers' (Old Mutual International and Generali International) contact personnel and updating Senior Management on a regular basis.
- Conducting market research and analysis to ascertain risk levels vis-à-vis portfolio risk to ensure sustainability of investments.
- Periodically visit high-net clients for portfolio review and regularly brief the managing director on various projects and progress.
- Conducting due diligence on potential Offshore providers who would want to partner in provision of Offshore products.
- Liaising with the Independent Financial Advisors for existing client visits with an aim of reviewing their portfolios on a quarterly basis
- Monitoring global market performance on a daily basis so as to guide the Research Department on markets to expose and allocate client holdings of mutual funds, exchange traded funds, structured notes and bonds
- Monitoring individual client portfolio performance with an aim of re-adjusting the portfolios so as to maximize returns on a quarterly basis.
- Issuing proposals as per stated investment objectives to prospective clients for mutual funds, exchange traded funds, structured notes and bonds
- Submitting a monthly article on behalf of the company to be published by Think Business magazine

# **Key Achievement:**

Actively involved in generating offshore investments ideas while taking ownership of them.

#### **Research Analyst**

Orchid Capital Ltd (Formerly Winton Investments), Aug 2012 - May 2015

## **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Conducting due diligence on potential Offshore providers who would want to partner in provision of Offshore products.
- Liaising with the Independent Financial Advisors for existing client visits with an aim of reviewing their portfolios on a quarterly basis
- Monitoring global market performance on a daily basis so as to guide the Research Department on markets to expose and allocate client holdings of mutual funds, exchange traded funds, structured notes and bonds

- Monitoring individual client portfolio performance with an aim of re-adjusting the portfolios so as to maximize returns on a quarterly basis.
- Issuing proposals as per stated investment objectives to prospective clients for mutual funds, exchange traded funds, structured notes and bonds
- Submitting a monthly article on behalf of the company to be published by Think Business magazine

# **Key Achievement:**

> Achieved positive returns for clients in the global market despite Greek government debt crisis.

# **OTHER INTERESTS**

- Travelling
- Reading

# **REFEREES**

Mr. Victor Chumo	Mr. Churchill Ogutu	Mr. Kevin Nyangate
Head of Investments Advisory	Economist	Dealing
Liaison Group	IC Asset Managers (Mauritius)	Apollo Group
Tel: +254 723 428 267	Tel: +254 711 796 739	Tel: +254 723 753 087
Vkta2010@gmail.com	schurchill.oduor@gmail.com	nyangatakevin@gmail.com